Inspired by a true story of faith and fortune.
Sarah's Oil is a drama film directed by Cyrus Nowrasteh.
Sarah Rector, an African-American girl born in Oklahoma Indian Territory in the early 1900s, believes
there is oil beneath the barren land she’s allotted, and her faith is proven right.
As greedy oil sharks close in, Sarah turns to her family, friends, and some Texas wildcatters to maintain control of her
oil-rich land, eventually becoming among the nation's first female African-American millionaires—at eleven years old.
Bert Smith, played by Zachary Levi.
Sarah, played by Naya Desir-Johnson.
Rose, played by Sonequa Martin-Green.
Devnan, played by Garret Dillahunt.
Kate Barnard, played by Bridget Regan.
Joe, played by Kenric Green.
Sarah's Oil is a 2025 American biographical drama film regarding Sarah Rector,
being directed, co-produced, and co-written by Cyrus Nowrasteh.
It is inspired by the 2014 book Searching for Sarah Rector: The
Richest Black Girl in America by Tonya Bolden.
It stars Zachary Levi, Naya Desir-Johnson, Sonequa
Martin-Green, and Garret Dillahunt.
Released theatrically by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer through Amazon MGM Studios on November 7, 2025, Sarah's Oil received generally positive reviews from critics and was fourth in the box office
during its opening week; eleventh highest domestic grossing movie during November 2025 out of 128 movies released that year; and 106 highest domestic grossing movie of 2025 .
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, based on true story, oil.
The tone is emotional.